Felipe Marin



https://pipe-mv.github.io/Resume/



: https://www.linkedin.com/in/felipe-marin-v/



pipemarin1@gmail.com

https://github.com/pipe-mv



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Proactive, diligent and meticulous Junior Front End Developer with ample knowledge of React JS and the entire software practice involved in the production of applications through this library. I have a passion for programming which I have demonstrated through years of self-study with commitment, initiative and desire to learn the different languages required to code applications.

Additionally, I possess proven ability to combine vision, decision-making and strong business acumen with well-developed project management and leadership qualities to support successful company operations.

Working effectively as a member of a team is important to me. In my previous positions I worked as an integral part of a team which together, worked towards common goals and targets. I have a proven track record working with projects in different industries and I am more than able to provide all my knowledge and enthusiasm to help support the team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ► HTML CSS SCSS Bootstrap (and other frameworks) JavaScript React JS Node.js SQL GitHub Webpack NPM •
- VsCode, Atom, Git, Github, ReactApp, Node and NPM package and Meta4 PeopleNet system (ERP).
- Proven knowledge of different Operating Systems and computer hardware.
- High proficient user of Microsoft Office Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project, Outlook and Power BI.
- Used different communication tools like Slack, Zoom, Skype, Microsoft Team and Cisco Webex Meetings.
- High knowledge and ability to use various types of Accounting and Financial systems such as; MYOB, XERO TMX, MoneyGram, Flightdeck Portal, and other banking portals.

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- High level of communication.
- Customer service.
- Negotiation.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer | Generation Australia | March 2023 - June 2023

I was accepted to the Generation Australia 12-week intensive program. Whilst this is also education, the commitment is a minimum of 30 hours per week with task and project requirements.

Tech skills learnt:

CSS3, HTML5, Vanilla JavaScript, VS Code, Git terminal (Git Bash), GitHub, npm and unit testing basics.

Additional skills:

Growth mindset, future orientation, effective communication, exposure to guest speakers, collaboration and more projects.

Data Coordinator | PetStock Pty | June 2021- September 2021

As a Data Coordinator for PETstock I was accountable for providing support with customized reports to the supply Chain department to make purchases and acquisitions decisions for the company.

Achievements

- Ensured master data accuracy across PETstock ERP and Warehouse Management System.
- Validated master data provided by suppliers.
- Collaborated with the Merchandising team to clean legacy product data.
- Used historical data and insights to slot products for all PETstock distribution centers.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to create reports for PETstock's Supply Chain department.
- Used advanced analysis to create and improve existing processes.
 Achievements.

Head of Accounting | Ucrania Ltd. Plantaciones Churido Ltd. | January 2002 March 2013

As Head of Accounting, I was accountable for the accounting and financial information in order to make the financial decisions for the company.

Achievements

- Structured and managed a project in order to redesign the payroll system for the company which involved the development of technology in order to achieve the project's target;
- Analysed and reviewed GST, tax and withholding declarations;
- Allocated staff and financial resources to ensure productivity of the company was kept at a high level;
- Managed and coordinated the financial resources of \$2.5 million dollars using banking portals and by relationships with senior banking managers;
- Prepared and submitted monthly and annual financial statements to company's CEO and government auditors;
- Modeled and projected the upcoming year's budget by comparing current budgets;
- Reduced the clearance from fourteen days to between three to five days by encouraging, motivating and leading a change in the management systems by reviewing and assessing the then payroll system;
- Reached successful agreements and solutions with the Workers' Union that prevented strikes against the company which would have been harmful for the company's finances and the workers' families.

Engineering Solutions Analyst

Enlace Operativo S.A. |

September

2010

February 2011

As Engineering Solutions Analyst, I was accountable for the software development and information management in order to ensure the technological development according to the client's needs.

Achievements

- Created and conducted training programs for customers upon implementation of payroll systems;
- Developed and managed different accounting software and systems;
- Ensured a high level of customer satisfaction;
- Managed reports required by several customers for their analysis;
- Worked in accordance with company procedures and met deadlines for task activities and goals.
 Achievements;
- Successfully designed, set up and reconfigured payroll systems for multiple companies with more than 300 workers;

Mail Administration | GU Health - Options Finance | January 2018- July 2018

As Mail administrator, I was accountable for the returned mail and the new mail to be sent, taking into account its personal information in order to ensure its successful delivery according to the client's information.

Achievements

- Classified the different returned mail and make the notes in the system according to the different types of mail and customer;
- Saved the returned mail that contains the member's cards in the secured locker by sorting them in an accurate order;
- Classified and organised the different mails the company was sending according to the customer and type of mail;
- Organised the mail to be sent through the post and enveloped securing the right documents and attachments to the correct customer with accuracy;

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

	COURSE	INSTITUTION	YEAR COMPLETED
•	Web Development	Generation Australia	2023
•	React development	General Assembly	2022
•	Postgraduate Diploma of Project Management	Pontifical Bolivarian University	2012
	Bachelor of Accounting	University of Medellin (Recognised by CPA Australia) Metropolitan Technologist Institute (Certified by Engineers Australia)	2009
	9		2004
	Telecommunications Technical Officer or		
	Technologist		

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Learning new programing languages and assisting to Meetups about technology, software and management
- I am a big fan of different sports such as NRL, AFL, F1, Soccer, Rugby, Tennis among others.
- Walking and nature explorer

REFERENCES: Available on request.